# WILLIAM DIEP

■ WillWebDesigns@gmail.com

www.williamdiep.me

**4** (408) 605-1266

SF Bay Area, CA

in www.linkedin.com/in/wdiep

Full Stack Developer (Front End Focus) with a love of design who has seven years of experience in systems administration and tech support, and ten years of experience in teaching and mentoring. Recent positions include providing customercentric tier 1 and 2 support with scopes of project management and consulting services. Passion for teaching, building, and learning new technologies.

# **Skills**

HTML5/CSS3

SASS

JavaScript/ES6

**j**Query

Python

**Templating Engines** 

Webpack

Gulp

Bootstrap 4

Foundation 6

Git

MVC Architecture
Content Management Systems
Responsive Web Design
Search Engine Optimization
MailChimp

Adobe Photoshop

NodeJS

MongoDB

Digital Ocean

**Amazon Web Services** 

Nginx

Apache

# **Education**

#### San lose State University

Bachelor of Science Health Science 2013 GPA 3.4/4.0

#### Foothill College

Associate of Science Computer Science 2018 GPA 3.85/4.0

### Front End Developer Code Camp (Cañada College)

2016

Enrolled in a 16-week immersive training program learning front-end programming, data structures, algorithms, & agile development

Collaborated in agile teams to plan and create websites and web apps

# **Experience**

#### theCoderSchool

San Jose & Fremont, CA · Jul 2017 to Current

Coding Instructor

• Instruct and mentor 6 - 16 year olds web development, game development, and data structures and algorithms using HTML5/ CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

#### Will's Web Designs

SF Bay Area, CA · May 2016 to Current

Full Stack Developer

- Design and full stack development of responsive websites and web apps, and database architecture for small businesses
- Consult with clients, provide scope of project, proposals, and statement of work

#### **NASA Ames Research Center**

Mountain View, CA · Jan 2013 to Jul 2013

Junior Web and Graphic designer (Intern)

- Generated, revised and, managed webpages for the Earth Science Division using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript. Improving web accessibility while providing administrative support to senior team members
- Collaboratively worked in a team of 5 to effectively create over 25 high-quality designs of brochures, posters, and presentations using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Photoshop in an aggressive onemonth time-frame resulting an increase of \$28K funding
- Coached four interns on a 1-1 basis on using MS Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Visio and Adobe Photoshop increasing team efficiency by ten fold

## GoFundMe

Redwood City, CA · Aug 2016 to Nov 2016

IT Administrator (Contract)

• Sole technician who provided technical support and systems administration to 100+ users in new office supporting executives, finance, marketing, and engineering departments

#### DominoComp Technology Source

San Jose, CA · Sep 2014 to Jan 2016

IT Support Specialist

- Provided tier 1 and 2 software and hardware support locally and remotely to 100+ clients
- Reduced help desk calls by 30% by developing end-user training and knowledge database

#### Citi's Sleepworld

San Jose, CA · Jun 2011 to Sep 2014

IT & Customer Services Support

- Provided desktop support and trained 25 staffs the efficiently use of business systems and peripherals improving weekly shipments by double
- Handled customer inquiries, billing concerns, service requests, and issued return merchandise authorizations

Foothill-De Anza Community College District

Cupertino, CA · Aug 2009 to Jun 2011